Guide to the Asa and Elna Spaulding Papers, 1909-1997 and undated, bulk 1935-1983 RL.01240
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Asa Spaulding Subgroup, 1909-1984 and undated, 331 boxes
  - North Carolina Mutual Files Series, 1911-1979, bulk 1945-1979, 67 boxes
    - The Whetstone. Issues, 1961-1982, Folders 7-9 of 9 (Box NCM-67)
    - Wholesale Insurance,1944-1945 (Box NCM-67)
    - Winston-Salem,1959-1963 (Box NCM-67)
    - Winston Mutual Life Insurance Co.,1940-1949 (Box NCM-67)
    - WSRC,1966-1967 (Box NCM-67)
    - WTIK,1953-1956 (Box NCM-67)
    - WTVD,1954-1957 (Box NCM-67)
    - Youth Fitness Commission of North Carolina,1960 (Box NCM-67)
  - Insurance Files Series, 1911-1973 and undated, bulk 1941-1968, 38 boxes
    Material documenting Spaulding's relationships with other insurance companies and his activities in national insurance organizations. Arranged alphabetically by name or topic. Of special note is the material about the National Insurance Association, which comprises almost half the series; although it was called the "National Negro Insurance Association" into the 1950s, all materials are filed under the heading "National Insurance Association."
    - American College of Life Underwriters,1947-1967 Mar., 5 folders (Box AI-1)
    - American Life Convention,1945-1966, Folders 1-3 of 8 (Box AI-1)
    - American Life Convention,1945-1966, Folders 4-8 of 8 (Box AI-2)
    - American Life Convention Manual,1963 (Box AI-2)
    - American Society of Chartered Life Underwriters,1964-1966 (Box AI-3)
    - Association of North Carolina Life Insurance Companies,1958 (Box AI-3)
    - Atlanta Life Insurance Company,1944-1945 (Box AI-3)
    - Banker's Fire and Casualty Insurance Company,1933-1968, Folders 1-7 of 8 (Box AI-3)
    - Banker's Fire and Casualty Company,1933-1968, Folder 8 of 8 (Box AI-4)
    - Controllers Institute of America,1947-1954 (Box AI-4)
    - Correspondence,1939-1965 (Box AI-4)
    - Dunbar Mutual Insurance Society,1936-1942 and undated, Folders 1-3 of 6 (Box AI-4)
    - Dunbar Mutual Insurance Society, Inc.1936-1942 and undated, Folders 4-6 of 6 (Box AI-5)
    - Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States,1963 (Box AI-5)
    - Federal Life Assurance Company, undated (Box AI-5)
    - Great Lakes Mutual Life Insurance Company,1936-1968 (Box AI-5)
    - Guaranty Life Insurance Company, 1957-1958 (Box AI-5)
    - Institute of Life Insurance
      - Clippings,1941 (Box AI-5)
      - Correspondence,1945-1969, Folders 1-3 of 6 (Box AI-5)
    - Institute of Life Insurance (Box AI-6)
      - Correspondence,1945-1969, Folders 4-6 of 6 (Box AI-6)
      - Miscellany,1945 (Box AI-6)
      - Pipeline, 1962-1966, Folders 1-2 of 5 (Box AI-6)
    - Institute of Life Insurance
      - Pipeline, 1962-1966, Folders 3-5 of 5 (Box AI-6)
      - Printed Material,1945-1967, Folders 1-3 of 5 (Box AI-6)
    - Institute of Life Insurance (Box AI-8)
      - Printed Material,1945-1967, Folders 4-5 of 5 (Box AI-8)
      - Research Forums,1964-1965 (Box AI-8)
    - Insurance Committee, Chamber of Commerce of the United States,1954 (Box AI-8)
    - The Insurance Index,1947-1964 (Box AI-8)
    - Insurance Almanac,1952-1962 (Box AI-8)
    - Insurance Hall of Fame,1968-1973 (Box AI-9)
    - Interracial Goodwill Insurance Fund,1943 (Box AI-9)
    - Life Insurance Agency Management Association
      - Consultation Service,1964 (Box AI-9)
      - Correspondence,1958-1968, Folders 1-4 of 8 (Box AI-9)
    - Life Insurance Agency Management Association (Box AI-10)
      - Correspondence,1958-1968, Folders 5-8 of 8 (Box AI-10)
      - Miscellany,1966, undated (Box AI-10)
      - Printed Material,1957-1966, Folders 1-2 of 6 (Box AI-10)
    - Life Insurance Agency Management Association (Box AI-11)
      - Printed Material1957-1966, Folders 3-6 of 6 (Box AI-11)
      - School for Agency Management,1948 (Box AI-11)
    - Life Insurance Association of America
      - Annual Meeting,1961-1966, Folders 1-2 of 5 (Box AI-11)
    - Life Insurance Association of America (Box AI-12)
      - Annual Meeting,1961-1966, Folders 3-5 of 5 (Box AI-12)
      - Correspondence,1955-1967, Folders 1-3 of 5 (Box AI-12)
    - Life Insurance Association of America (Box AI-13)
      - Correspondence,1955-1967, Folders 4-5 of 5 (Box AI-13)
      - Miscellany,1963-1964 (Box AI-13)
      - Newsletters,1961-1967, 4 folders (Box AI-13)
      - Printed Material,1959-1968, Folder 1 of 4 (Box AI-13)
    - Life Insurance Association of America (Box AI-14)
      - Printed Material,1959-1968, Folders 2-4 of 4 (Box AI-14)
      - Reports,1962-1967 (Box AI-14)
    - Life Insurance Investors, Inc., 1978 (Box AI-14)
    - Life Office Management Association
      - Bulletin,1960-1966, 2 folders (Box AI-14)
      - Combination Company Review,1964-1966 (Box AI-14)
      - Correspondence,1951-1971, Folder 1 of 4 (Box AI-14)
    - Life Office Management Association (Box AI-15)
      - Correspondence,1951-1971, Folders 2-4 of 4 (Box AI-15)
      - Cost Committee,1950-1956 (Box AI-15)
      - Equipment Review,1960-1966 (Box AI-15)
      - Group Administration Topics,1962-1966 (Box AI-15)
      - Keynotes,1961-1966 (Box AI-15)
      - Miscellany, undated (Box AI-15)
    - Life Office Management Association (Box AI-16)
      - Personnel Quarterly,1961-1966 (Box AI-16)
      - Planning Quarterly,1961-1966 (Box AI-16)
      - Printed Material,1937-1967, 3 folders (Box AI-16)
      - Supervisory Development Course,1962 (Box AI-16)
      - Supervisory Training Manual,1965 (Box AI-16)
    - Lincoln National Life Insurance Company,1946-1966 (Box AI-16)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company,1937-1948 (Box AI-16)
    - Miscellany,1944-1965 and undated (Box AI-16)
    - National Association of Insurance Commissioners,1962 (Box AI-17)
    - National Insurance Association
      - Chronological files,1934-1965 and undated, Folders 1-6 of 23 (Box AI-17)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-18)
      - Chronological files,1934-1965 and undated, Folders 7-13 of 23 (Box AI-18)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-19)
      - Chronological files,1934-1965 and undated, Folders 14-20 of 23 (Box AI-19)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-20)
      - Chronological files,1934-1965 and undated, Folders 21-23 of 23 (Box AI-20)
      - Addresses,1935-1967, 2 folders (Box AI-20)
      - Annual Conventions,1936-1969, Folders 1-2 of 10 (Box AI-20)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-21)
      - Annual Conventions,1936-1969, Folders 3-8 of 10 (Box AI-21)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-22)
      - Annual Conventions,1936-1969, Folders 9-10 of 10 (Box AI-22)
      - Anti-Inflation Campaign Committee,1943 (Box AI-22)
      - Clearing House Committee,1942 (Box AI-22)
      - Clippings,1934-1959 (Box AI-22)
      - Committee on Conciliation and Arbitration,1941-1943 (Box AI-22)
      - Committee on Legislation, Taxation, and Government Regulation,1942 (Box AI-22)
      - Committee on the Study of Annual Dues,1941-1943 (Box AI-22)
      - Correspondence,1936-1982 and undated, Folders 1-2 of 5 (Box AI-22)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-23)
      - Correspondence,1936-1982 and undated, Folders 3-5 of 5 (Box AI-23)
      - Double Anniversary Commission,1960 (Box AI-23)
      - Executive Committee,1941-1968 (Box AI-23)
      - Financial Papers,1953-1954 (Box AI-23)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-24)
      - Five Year Planning Committee,1941 (Box AI-24)
      - Food for Freedom,1942-1943 (Box AI-24)
      - Historical Commission,1955-1959 (Box AI-24)
      - Invitations to Address Convention,1955 (Box AI-24)
      - Labor Appreciation Week,1943 (Box AI-24)
      - National Insurance Association "Life Insurance an Important Factor in Our National Life,"1941 (Box AI-24)
      - Re: Life Insurance Premiums as a Deductible Item in Income Tax Proposal,1942-1943 (Box AI-24)
      - Murray J. Marvin, Executive Director,1951-1956 (Box AI-24)
      - Meeting of Major Company Officials,1941-1942 (Box AI-24)
      - Mergers,1960 (Box AI-24)
      - Miscellany, undated (Box AI-24)
      - National Collection Month Committee,1941-1943 (Box AI-24)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-25)
      - National Defense Vigilance Committee,1941-1942 (Box AI-25)
      - National Insurance Week,1954-1962 (Box AI-25)
      - National Negro Insurance Bonds and Stamps Committee,1941-1943 (Box AI-25)
      - National Negro Insurance Week,1940-1946, 2 folders (Box AI-25)
      - National War Bond Rally,1941-1944, Folders 1-2 of 4 (Box AI-25)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-26)
      - National War Bond Rally,1941-1944, Folders 3-4 of 4 (Box AI-26)
      - Negro Mortality Study,1940-1962 (Box AI-26)
      - Organization Committee,1962-1963 (Box AI-26)
      - Premium Rates, Discussion,1935 (Box AI-26)
      - Printed Material,1935-1971 (Box AI-26)
      - Procedure in Claim Adjustments, Investigation, etc., undated (Box AI-26)
      - Proclamations,1942-1943 (Box AI-26)
      - Program Committee,1941-1964, Folders 1-2 of 19 (Box AI-26)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-27)
      - Program Committee,1941-1964, Folders 3-9 of 19 (Box AI-27)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-28)
      - Program Committee,1941-1964, Folders 10-15 of 19 (Box AI-28)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-29)
      - Program Committee,1941-1964, Folders 16-19 of 19 (Box AI-29)
      - Public Relations Committee,1942-1943 (Box AI-29)
      - Publicity,1941-1943, Folder 1 of 2 (Box AI-29)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-30)
      - Publicity,1941-1943, Folder 2 of 2 (Box AI-30)
      - Questionnaires,1941-1960 (Box AI-30)
      - Releases,1942-1943 (Box AI-30)
      - Reports and Statements,1927-1953 (Box AI-30)
      - Republican National Committee,1954 Jan.-Sept., 2 folders (Box AI-30)
      - Rosters,1944-1962 (Box AI-30)
      - Scrapbook,1954 (Box AI-30)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-31)
      - Secretary,1941-1944, 2 folders (Box AI-31)
      - Service Bulletin,1941-1948 (Box AI-31)
      - Re: Smaller Insurance Companies,1941 (Box AI-31)
      - Special Releases,1941-1943, 2 folders (Box AI-31)
      - Speeches Concerning Agency,1963-1964 (Box AI-31)
      - Sponsorships,1954-1956, Folder 1 of 2 (Box AI-31)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-32)
      - Sponsorships,1954-1956, Folder 2 of 2 (Box AI-32)
      - Re: Tax Measure Affecting Life Insurance Companies,1942-1943 (Box AI-32)
      - Technician's Conferences,1959-1960 (Box AI-32)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-33)
      - Technicians' Institute,1948-1950, 3 folders (Box AI-33)
      - Time and Place Committee,1958-1960, 3 folders (Box AI-33)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-34)
      - Treasurer,1942 -1943 (Box AI-34)
      - Underwriters' Forum,1946 (Box AI-34)
      - War Manpower Committee,1941-1943 (Box AI-34)
      - War Manpower Program,1943-1944 (Box AI-34)
      - War Prisoners' Fund,1942 (Box AI-34)
    - National Insurance Association (Box AI-35)
      - Wings Over Jordan,1943 -1946, 2 folders (Box AI-35)
    - National Underwriter Company,1963 (Box AI-35)
    - Negro Operated Life Insurance Companies,1940-1958 (Box AI-35)
    - Pilot Life Insurance Company,1964 (Box AI-36)
    - Republic National Life Insurance Company,1963-1966 (Box AI-36)
    - Society of Actuaries,1942-1963, 2 folders (Box AI-36)
    - Southern Standard Insurance Company,1930-1933 (Box AI-36)
    - Union Insurance and Realty Company,1942-1946 (Box AI-37)
    - Universal Underwriters Services, Inc.,1965 (Box AI-37)
    - Victory Mutual Life Insurance Company,1943-1944 (Box AI-37)
    - Virginia,1944 (Box AI-37)
    - Virginia Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Co,1945 (Box AI-37)
    - Volunteer State Life Insurance Co.,1964-1968 (Box AI-38)
    - Winston Mutual Life Insurance Co.,1911 and undated, 6 folders (Box AI-38)
  - Subject Files Series, 1929-1984 and undated, 15 boxes
    A miscellany of documents from throughout Asa Spaulding's career. Included here are clippings and printed materials he collected on a wide range of interests; records of his travels; some income tax records; and an extensive collection of programs indicating the wide range of events in which the Spauldings participated. Also filed here is additional biographical information about himself and his family that was apparently not gathered as part of his research for his uncompleted autobiography that appears in the Writings and Speeches Series. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Alliance with Third World Countries,1979 (Box AS-1)
    - Awards,1943-1982 and undated, 3 folders (Box AS-1)
    - Biographical: articles, clippings, and press releases about Asa T. Spaulding,1938-1983 and undated, 3 folders (Box AS-1)
      Material apparently not specifically gathered for Spaulding's research on his autobiography. For more detailed biographical information, see "Autobiography" folders in Writings and Speeches Series.
    - Blacks and History,1956-1962 (Box AS-1)
    - Blacks in Business,1957-1979 (Box AS-2)
    - C (miscellany),1978-1981 and undated (Box AS-2)
    - Calendars, Appointments, and Contacts,1969-1982 and undated, 4 folders (Box AS-2)
    - Clippings,1929-1983 and undated, Folders 1-5 of 9 (Box AS-3)
    - Clippings,1929-1983 and undated, Folders 6-9 of 9 (Box AS-4)
    - Committee Report: Program in the Economics and Politics of Aging Conferences,1979 (Box AS-4)
    - Conferences,1963-1981 (Box AS-4)
    - Courses of Study,1930-1963, Folder 1 of 6 (Box AS-4)
    - Courses of Study,1930-1963, Folders 2-6 of 6 (Box AS-5)
    - D (miscellany) (Box AS-5)
    - Democratic National Convention,1980 Aug. (Box AS-6)
    - Diplomatic Affairs,1962, 1978 (Box AS-6)
    - Durham, miscellaneous documents and clippings,1954-1980 (Box AS-6)
    - Energy Security Act,1980 (Box AS-6)
    - Events and Participation,1981-1984 (Box AS-6)
    - F (miscellany),1976-1979 and undated (Box AS-6)
    - Fisher, Miles Mark,1965-1983 (Box AS-6)
    - G (miscellany),1981-1983 (Box AS-6)
    - H-I (miscellany),1975-1982 (Box AS-6)
    - Income Tax Returns,1933, 1943, 1959, 1963, 1979, 1981-1982, 7 folders (Box AS-7)
    - India,1956 (Box AS-7)
    - Information about Others: Dr. Geraldine Pittman Woods,1969-1977 (Box AS-7)
    - Information about Others,1955-1982 and undated, 3 folders (Box AS-7)
    - Israel,1980-1983 (Box AS-8)
    - J (miscellany),1965, 1983 (Box AS-8)
    - King Memorial Center Announcement,1968 (Box AS-8)
    - Kress Building (Durham), undated (Box AS-8)
    - Law, undated (Box AS-8)
    - Leadership Development Planning,1981 (Box AS-8)
    - Legislation (miscellany),1965-1974 and undated (Box AS-8)
    - Liberia,1956, 1976 (Box AS-8)
    - Liberia Today,1958-1960 (Box AS-8)
    - Liberian Letter,1962-1964 (Box AS-8)
    - Lincoln, C. Eric,1980-1982 (Box AS-8)
    - M (miscellany),1968-1980 (Box AS-8)
    - McMillan, William M.,1965 (Box AS-8)
    - Medical Papers,1975-1979 (Box AS-8)
    - Memorabilia, undated (Box AS-8)
    - N (miscellany), 1942, 1973-1982 and undated (Box AS-9)
    - Nigeria,1964-1980 (Box AS-9)
    - Pakistan,1964 (Box AS-9)
    - Peace in the Middle East,1978-1982 (Box AS-9)
    - Political Campaigns: 1968 Candidacy for Durham County Commissioner,1968 (Box AS-9)
    - Political Campaigns: 1971 Candidacy for Mayor of Durham,1970-1971, Folders 1-3 of 7 (Box AS-9)
    - Political Campaigns: 1971 Candidacy for Mayor of Durham,1970-1971, Folders 4-7 of 7 (Box AS-10)
    - Political Campaigns: various candidates,1976-1981 (Box AS-10)
    - Political Issues, miscellaneous,1974-1981 (Box AS-10)
    - President's Club Convention in Nassau,1966-1967 (Box AS-10)
    - Programs,1953-1983, Folders 1-14 of 31 (Box AS-11)
    - Programs,1953-1983, Folders 15-22 of 31 (Box AS-12)
    - Programs,1953-1983, Folders 23-28 of 31 (Box AS-13)
    - Programs,1953-1983, Folders 29-31 of 31 (Box AS-14)
    - S (miscellaneous),1970-1979 (Box AS-14)
    - Sadat, Anwar,1981 (Box AS-14)
    - South Africa trip,1974 (Box AS-14)
    - Tar Heel of the Week: Correspondence and Clippings,1975 (Box AS-14)
    - Travel,1956 (Box AS-14)
    - U-V (miscellany),1947-1981 and undated (Box AS-14)
    - Urban Renewal,1957-1962, 2 folders (Box AS-15)
    - W-Z and unidentified (miscellany),1979-1981 and undated (Box AS-15)
    - Whiteville, N.C., miscellany,1976-1979 (Box AS-15)
  - Photographic Materials Series, 1940-1983 and undated, 4 boxes
    Arranged in subseries that correspond to the appropriate series in the top level structure of the Asa Spaulding Subgroup. Arrangement is then alphabetical by name or topic within each of these subseries. Note that several folders of photographs whose subject and/or date could not be determined appear at the end of the Subject Files subseries.
    - Correspondence Subseries,1967-1979
      - Broyhill, James T., 1971 (Box APM-1)
      - Carter, Jimmy, 1979 (Box APM-1)
      - Duke, Angier Biddle, 1978 (Box APM-1)
      - Germany, trip to,1967 (Box APM-1)
      - Helms, Jesse, 1975 (Box APM-1)
    - Writings and Speeches Subseries,1981
      - Autobiography, Research Materials:Spaulding FamilyReunion,1981 (Box APM-1)
    - Organizations Subseries,1956-1981 and undated
      - Committee on State and Local Government Cooperation, 1973 (Box APM-1)
      - Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, 1979 (Box APM-1)
      - Howard University, 1973-1981 and undated, 2 folders (Box APM-1)
      - National Conference of Christians and Jews, undated (Box APM-1)
      - Omega Psi Phi, 1967 and undated (Box APM-1)
      - People-to-People,1969 (Box APM-1)
      - Religious News Service, undated (Box APM-1)
      - Southeastern Community College, 1969 (Box APM-1)
      - United States Delegation, UNESCO General Conference, New Delhi, India,1956 (Box APM-1)
        In addition to official photographs, personal photographs and snapshots of the Spauldings' trip to India are included here.
      - United States Delegation to Liberian Inaugural Ceremony, 1956 (Box APM-1)
      - United States Information Agency. Exhibit Photographs,1959 (Box APM-2)
      - White Rock Baptist Church, 1965-1980 and undated (Box APM-2)
    - North Carolina Mutual Files Subseries,1943-1978 and undated
      - Board of Directors,1943 (Box APM-2)
      - Dedication of Home Office Building,1966, 3 folders (Box APM-2)
      - Jolaoso, Olumiji,, Ambassador of Nigeria,1978 (Box APM-3)
      - Spaulding, Asa. Portraits in his office and at various functions,1959 and undated (Box APM-3)
      - Toure, Soukou,President of Guinea,1967 and undated (Box APM-3)
    - Insurance Files Subseries,1950-1961
      - Jackson Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1950 (Box APM-3)
      - National Insurance Association,circa 1953-1961 (Box APM-3)
        PresidentDwight D. Eisenhoweris pictured in an undated photograph.
    - Subject Files Subseries,1940-1983 and undated
      - Awards,1971-1980 (Box APM-3)
        Portraits of the Spauldings receiving awards and of honors ceremonies.
      - Information about others, undated (Box APM-3)
        Portraits and publicity about executives of various companies.
      - Spaulding, Asa T.Portraits,1940-1969 and undated (Box APM-3)
      - Spaulding Family Photographs,1954-1976 and undated (Box APM-3)
        Note: photographs of the 1981 Spaulding Family reunion were considered part of Asa Spaulding's research material for his unpublished autobiography and are housed in the Writings and Speeches Subseries under "Autobiography."
      - Unidentified and miscellaneous photographs,1950-1983 and undated, 5 folders (Box APM-4)
  - Audiovisual Materials Series, 1950-1980s and undated, 4 boxes
    Audiotapes, audio cassettes, videotapes, and videocassettes documenting Spaulding's career and private life. Arranged in separate subseries for audio and video materials.
    - Audio Materials Subseries,1968-1981 and undated
      Arranged in subseries that correspond to the appropriate series in the top level structure of the Asa Spaulding Subgroup. Arrangement is then alphabetical by name or topic within each of these subseries.
      - Writings and Speeches Sub-subseries (Original Copies),1979 and undated (Box AV-1)
        Closed. Refer to Use Copies UC1-UC3 for access.
        - OR1, tapes I and II. Genealogy of Asa T. Spaulding, Sr., tapes I and II, undated (2 audio cassettes) (Box AV-1)
        - OR2. Interview of Asa T. Spaulding, Sr., by Dr. Walter Weare,1979 Apr. 14-15 (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
        - OR3.Lay Sermon by Asa Spaulding, Sr. and Interview of Atty. Travis Porter by Asa Spaulding, Jr., undated (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
      - North Carolina Mutual Sub-subseries (Original Copies),1981
        Closed. Refer to Use Copy UC4 for access.
        - OR4.Dedication of the N.C. Mutual New Home Office Building, 1981. (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
      - Subject Files Sub-subseries (Original Copies),1977-1981 and undated
        Closed. Refer to Use Copies UC5-UC11 for access.
        - OR5.Asa Spaulding: Courtship and Marriage, undated (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
        - OR6.Asa Spaulding: His Family and Church Work, undated (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
        - OR7.Community Profile: Asa Spaulding, Sr., undated Oct. 29 (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
        - OR8. Interview of Asa Spaulding by Margaret Webb, WPTF radio station, circa 1978 Jan. Raleigh, N.C.: Durham Life Broadcasting Service, 1978 (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
        - OR9.Kin and Communities: Sixth International Symposium of the Smithsonian Institution, 1977 June 14 (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
        - OR10.Lumbee the Lowry's and Danny Chavis, 1979 Apr. 11 (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
        - OR11.Welches Creek Township History and The Henry Berry Lowry Story, 1981 June 12 (Audio cassette) (Box AV-1)
      - Writings and Speeches Sub-subseries (Original Copies),1979 and undated
        Closed. Refer to Use Copies in the appropriate subseries for access to audio cassettes. For audio micro-cassettes and reel-to-reel tapes listed here, use copies will be made on request.
        - OR12. Dr. Weare interviewed,1979 Apr. 14-15 (Micro-cassette) (Box AV-4)
        - OR13.Journey of My Life, undated (Micro-cassette) (Box AV-4)
        - OR14.Lowry Genealogy, undated (Micro-cassette) (Box AV-4)
        - OR15, tapes I and II,Noble Ancestry, undated (2 micro-cassettes) (Box AV-4)
        - OR16.A Personal Approach to Racial Equality, by Asa T. Spaulding. Omaha, Neb.: Opinion Institute, undated The Sounds of Learning, reel 630 (Reel-to-reel audiotape) (Box AV-4)
        - OR17.Post-war genealogy, undated (Micro-cassette) (Box AV-4)
        - OR18. Untitled, undated (Micro-cassette) (Box AV-4)
      - North Carolina Mutual Sub-subseries (Original Copies), undated
        Closed. Refer to Use Copies in the appropriate subseries for access to audiocassettes. For audio micro-cassettes and reel-to-reel tapes listed here, use copies will be made on request.
        - OR19. Re: purchase of "Four Acres" for NCM H.O. Bldg., undated (Micro-cassette) (Box AV-4)
      - Subject Files Sub-subseries (Original Copies),1968, 1979
        - OR20.Analogue, program with Asa Spaulding participating, 1968 Apr. 10. New York: National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1968 (Reel-to-reel audio tape, 29:21") (Box AV-4)
        - OR21, tapes I, II, and III. Gerontology Conference,1979 (3 micro-cassettes) (Box AV-4)
        - Master copies MC1-MC11. (Box AV-2)
          Closed. Refer to Use Copies UC1-UC11 for access.
        - Use copies UC1-UC11. (Box AV-3)
          Open to research. Refer to original copies OC1-OC11 above for container list.
    - Video Materials Subseries,1957-1958 and undated
      Original copies of videocassette materials.
      Closed. Use copies will be made on request.
      - Subject Files Sub-subseries,1957-1958 and undated
        - OR22. Untitled, circa 1957-1958 (16mm film, b/w, 2 reels) (Box AV-4)